本视频由SuperBart听译
Hi.
ヾ(´･ω･｀)ﾉ
Let me show you how rockets travel in space even there is no air to fly on.
我来讲一下火箭在真空中升天的原理
Rockets have engines that push out a lot of material at very high speed.
火箭的引擎可以喷出大量的高速气流
According to Newton Third Law, for every action, there's a equal and opposite reaction.
根据牛顿第三定律，所有的力都有一个等大反向的作用力
So for example, if you're pushing the wall,
举个例子，如果你推着墙的话
The wall can push you back with the exact same force.
墙会给你一个等大反向的作用力
<-----------O------------>
墙对老爸的作用力      质点大概位置        老爸对墙的力
That's why nothing moves.
所以没有东西会被移动
Here, I have a mouse trap that is put on the LEGO wheels,
这里，我在乐高车上放了一个老鼠夹
so, (it) can move around easily.
你看，这辆车可以随意推动
见 多 不 怪
Let me trigger it.
我现在要触发开关了
See, it stays around the same area.
看，车还在原来的地方
I have take three marbles together
我现在把三个球绑在了一起
to put on the back of the mousetrap, for it to do them.
放在了老鼠夹的后面，以备展示
See, the marble shoot that way and the mousetrap jumps the other way as the reaction.
看，那三个球朝那飞去了，而老鼠夹向相反的方向移动了
Similarly in space, our rockets has to shoot a ton of burning gas, (which is) very fast.
同理，在太空中，火箭向后快速喷出大量的气体
And in reaction, the rocket is pushed forward.
进而，火箭被推上了天
AND YOU DON'T NEED ANY AIR FOR THIS TO HAPPEN.
而这过程你根本就不需要用空气嘛o(≧口≦)o
So in vacuum space, the rocket should moves forward. The end:-)
所以在真空的太空中，火箭能够升天。我讲完啦:-)